Why are Russians so slightly
Почему русские такие чуть-чуть
aggressive, not aggressive, they are, they
агрессивные не агрессив есть они они
believe that everyone who is short is not Russian,
считают что все кто короче не русские
they are like some kind of
они типа какие-то
inferior, I am not from Russia.
неполноценный я из России
Why why the American flag sconce,
не Почему почему американский флаг бра
why am I originally from Rostov, I live just in
по что я родом из Ростова живу просто в
California, 18 years old, where are you from? And I am  from China
Калифорнии 18 лет вы откуда А я из Китая
The dude got his hands on an iPhone Yes, and
Чувак дорвался короче к Айфону Да и
look, it’s
смотри эфе
emitting English, not me, in short, I
рует English не я короче так с тобой
want to talk to you in Russian, why are you
хочу поговорить по-русски почему ты
from, Ukrainian, what, and Ukrainian, Ukrainian, where are
откуда украинец что а украинец украинска
you from? I’m from China, what kind of China,
Ты откуда Я из Китая Да какой Китая
look at you, you’re
посмотри на себя ты
drilling, brother, in short, now I’m studying  in
бурят брат короче сейчас я учусь в
Moscow, in Rostov, in short, the Buryats studied
Москве у меня в Ростове короче учились
in short, the storm Hey Yes, please pass
короче буря Эй Да пас пожалуйста
now, wait, wait, okay
сейчас сечас подождите подождите хорошо
Look, you are drilling from the Unu,
Ты посмотри Ты бурят из уну
yes, let me, let me go
да да давай дай мне дай мне чтоб я пошл
further Yes, you printed something for yourself,
даль Да ты что-то напечатал себе
in short, now, believe it, I don’t believe it  if
короче сейчас вери не не верю если мже
they barely understood Russian, and whoever
они русский еле-еле понимали а кто
understood, they spoke with such an accent that it was
понимал то с акцентом таким говорили
scary, you’re definitely not
страшным ты точно не
Chinese. In short, I’m a Pona and a Kazakh. I was just
китаец Короче я пона и казах Я просто
born in Sydney, you know where the
родился в сидне знаешь где находится
Uyghur is, maybe not.
Уйгур может нет Я казах я пона я не
blue Yes, there are
Уйгур там уйгуры а не казахи в сине Да
a lot of Kazakhs, a lot of Uyghurs, there are no Kazakhs there,
много казахов много уйгуров нету там
almost in Smydi, there are
почти в смы ди
Kazakhs there. No, not all Uyghurs are still
там казахов Нет не все уйгуры ещё
Chinese, bana, a lot of Chinese are also
китайцы бана очень много китайцев ещё
Kazakhs. I was born there, I know. Show me the
казахов Я же родился там я я знаю Покажи
place of birth where it
место рождения где
is written
написано
worse now here
хуже сейчас здесь
Sinn Yes Sinn really Yes really And
синн Да синн действительно Да реально А
what  I didn’t go to Russia to Kazakhstan Well,
что в Россию поехал не в Казахстан Ну
in short,
что короче
I thought, like in Russia, maybe study
Я думал типа в России может быть изучать
Russian, you know what in
русский язык чисто знаешь по что в
Kazakhstan, but they have an accent Well, I don’t
Казахстане но у них есть акцент Ну не
know Well,
знаю Ну
like in Russia, we don’t like people like you there
типа в России у нас там таких как ты не
Yes, I know it’s like that  yes, this is
любят Да я знаю это такое да а это
a kid from where he is from Uzbekistan
пацанчик откуда он из Узбекистана
Uzbekistan too Uh-
Узбекистана тоже
huh No Uzbek And no jik Arab [ __ ] Arab
Угу Нет узбек А нет жик араб бля араб А
Well show him here come on come on
ну покажи его сюда давай давай давай
brother come
брат иди
here now Where are you from brother you are from
сюда сейчас Ты откуда будешь брат ты из
Ukraine I’m not myself I’m from Rostov I live in
Украина я сам не Я сам из Ростова живу в
California that’s there  Ukraine is worth it
Калифорнии это там Украина стоит потому
because I installed a VPN with Ukrainians, I communicated,
что я ставил VPN с украинцами общался
so it lights up, yes And I understand that you are
поэтому светится да А я понял ты пона
Russian, yes, yes, well, well, how can I
русский да да Ну как на Ну как тебе
tell you, it’s difficult, my dad is
сказать у меня сложно у меня папа
Russian, and Kara’s mom can do it
русский Так а мама Кара колпачка может
You know, kapachka,
Ты знаешь капачка
yes, there is Karakalpakstan in Uzbekistan
да да в Узбекистане есть каракалпакстан
but the Karakalpaks are Turks who are closer to the
но каракалпаки они тюрки которые ближе к
Kazakhs yes yes How did you know I mean
казахам да да Откуда ты узнал В смысле
I found out My mother is from a Karakal pack Oh
узнал У меня мама из каракал пачка О
cool I know Iu Naro region Karakalpakstan I
круто знаю ию Наро регион каракалпакстан
know yes yes there were still unrest they
знаю да ти Да там ещ волнения были они
want to separate from Uzbekistan
хотят отделяться от Узбекистана
Arab You are an Arab from where an Arab like a Sakha
араб Ты араб откуда араб типа саханский
Arab  seriously Samarkan is an Arab he is a Samarkan
араб серьёзно Самаркан араб он Самаркан
Jew there are Jews there there were no Arabs
еврей там евреи там арабов не
there were no Jews
было евреев нет
there Samarkan there is a classical one there
Самаркан там классическая это в
was a Jewish community in Samarkand a
Самарканде была Еврейской община ещё
long time ago He is a huge Jew
давным-давно Огромно он еврей
[music]
[музыка]
in short brother How did you learn a lot of
короче брат Откуда ты узнал много
stories I tell myself Look my father
историй я себе говорю Смотри у меня отец
he was he  Russian and from Rostov, in
он был он русский так и с Ростова он в
Soviet times he served in Uzbekistan
советское время служил в Узбекистане там
where Karakalpakstan met my
где каракалпакстан познакомился с моей
mother She is Karakol tutu in and they
мамой Она Каракол пачка во и они
moved to Rostov, you see, I’m
переехали в Ростов у меня вот видишь я
also a little bit, well, it’s like I took more after my dad,
тоже немножко ну как бы я больше в папу
so it’s more like
пошёл поэтому типа больше на похож у
mine  at school, like when I
меня вот в школе типа когда я когда ещё
was still in elementary school, I looked more
был в младших классах я боле был похож
like Kara Kolpak and then somehow it
на Кара колпака а потом как-то оно там
transformed there and became more
трансформировалось больше на папу стал
like my dad, and we had this at school, they also
похож и у нас вот это в школе они тоже
used to say these Russians that you
посто там эти русские говорили которые
know all the time
знаешь постоянно
Yes  always a Russian type of eye still
Да всегда русский го типа глазный ещё
like e
как е
why why Russians are so slightly
ещ Почему русские такие чуть-чуть
aggressive
агрессив
they don’t think that everyone who is not
нере считат что все кто короче не
Russian is like some kind of inferior
русские они типа какие-то неполноценные
and for example at our school it
и вот например у нас в школе так вот
turns out like this Mom came because
получается Мама приходила потому что
mom mainly attended parenting  meetings
мама в основном на родительские собрания
came and not Dad, well, usually mothers
приходила а не Папа ну обычно мамы
come. Yes, and there these Russians, like mothers, are
приходят Да и там эти русские типа мамы
also like, oh, damn, they came in large numbers there,
тоже такие о типа блин понаехали туда
you know, like they came in large numbers, like, well, in the
знаешь о такие как понаехали типа ну в
Soviet Union. They were all like
Советском Союзе Они же все типа были
one country, you know, like, and here they are there, you came in large numbers,
одна страна знаешь типа и тут они там вы
we came to you  there, in short, we
понаехали мы вам там то мы вам короче
have this for you. And in America, in America, I
есть такое А в Америку в Америку я сюда
came here, here you generally understand that you are
приехал тут вообще понимаешь тут что ты
a Karakalpak, that you are, in short, an Indian, that you are a
каракалпак что ты короче индеец что ты
Buryat, that you are Russian, in general, everyone Everyone,
этот бурят что ты русский вообще все Все
in short, seems to live normally and
короче себе типа живут нормально и
develop Yes, because I lived in the USA  2
развиваются Да потому что я жил в США 2
years earlier Well, a year and a half
года раньше Ну полтора года
earlier, Dada understood Like an intern like
раньше Дада понял Типа стажёр типа
programs You know this, what is this
программ Ты знаешь это что такое-то
still now, well, the Russian language is
ещё сейчас ну русский язык для меня
very difficult for me, but aculiation yes how to
очень сложно но акули зация да как
say Like pronunciation pronunciation
сказать Типа произношение произношение
but all the teachers think like I’m
но все преподавательницы думают типа я
purely you look You can see  I wanted to say the word
чисто по ты вид Ты видно хотел слово
articulation to say
артикуляция сказать артикуляция
articulation articulation very purely they also say
артикуляция очень чисто ещё они говорят
like, well, teacher they say like Oh,
типа ну преподаватель они говорят типа О
what are you from Kazakhstan what not from Cindy
ты что ты из Казахстана что нет из Синди
also Cindy - what city else From
ещё Синди - это какой город ещё Из
what city from Kazakhstan
какого города из Казахстана
Why why do they always think Kazakhstan I
Почему почему всегда думают Казахстана
don’t know so many Russians they  They don’t even
не знаю так многие русские они даже не
know that in China there is the Ur
знают что в Китае есть вот сидя урский
Autonomous Okrug, and the Turks live there too. Yes, this
автономный округ Да и там тюрки живут Да
is a historical region. This is
что это исторический регион Вот это
Turkestan, figuratively it was called in the
Туркестан там образно он назывался во
east of a
восточ
hundred. Brother, you’re great,
ста Брат ты же молодец
brother,
брат
code 9, they say you’re there, all these
9 кода там говорят вы там эти всякие там
Uzbeks, Uyghurs, Kazakhs, you  there, we were there
узбеки уйгуры казахи вы там э были там
We Russians brought you culture and so
Мы русские вам принесли культуру и так
on Yes, I’m telling the Russians Look,
дальше Да я вот русским говорю Смотри
when there were Tatar-Mongols and there
когда было татаро-монголы да Москвы ещё
was no Moscow yet, the Russians were running in the forests somewhere Yes,
не было русские в лесах где-то бегали Да
but the Uyghurs already had a letter and a Uyghur
а у уйгуров уже Письмо было да уйгурское
letter like yes there in Chagatai
письмо типа да там на чагатайский
Brother, you even know the Chagatai language
Брат ты даже знаешь чагатайский язык
Nune Well, I studied the history of my people,
Нуне Ну я изучал историю своих
too, bound with neither so what are
тоже переплета с ни так
you working now or not Well, how can I
что сейчас ты работаешь или нет Ну как
say Like a teacher, I am, yes I am, I am a
сказать Типа преподаватель я да я Я
teacher of anthropology at
преподаватель антропологии в
the University of
университете
Sacramento What is your name Yes, you can
Сакраменто Как вас зовут Да можно можно
Andrey Andrey It’s very nice
Андрей Андрей Очень приятно
to meet you why Well  that like I
познакомиться почему Ну что как у меня
have friends, like they’re all Chinese, they kind of
есть друзья Типа все китайцы они типа
lived in Satu, they all say the sun is very
жили Сату они все говорят Солнце очень
hot, the weather is very good, I know it’s
жарко ещё погода Очень хорошая я знаю у
in my department, yes it works, well, I don’t
меня вот на кафедре Да работает Ну я не
know how he had a name in China, but here
знаю как у него в Китае было имя но тут
he took the name for himself because  that many of the
он взял имя себе потому что многие
Chinese who come here, they
китайцы которые у нас сюда приезжают они
take the European name, Yes, he’s
берут Европе Зро нае имя Да вот он
called John Wu, his surname is Wu, and he
называется Джон Ву фамилия у него ву А
took the name John, that is, they take the
имя взял Джон то есть они берут
European one, and there are many here, and
именно европей сирова ие вот тут многие
now I’ll tell you where he’s from,
есть то он сейчас скажу он откуда он из
this Nanjing  the city of Nanjing is in the south, the south is the
этот нанкин город нанкин это ю да юг
southern capital, he said Nanjing like
южная столица он говорил нанкин типа
Dara, you’re great, I didn’t
Дара ты ты молодец вообще не
think at all now I’m in shock, in short
думал сейчас я в шоке короче
Amazing, many Russians, you know, think that
Amazing русские многие знаешь думают что
only the Chinese live in China, they don’t
в Китае живут одни китайцы они не
understand that there are huge territories there, that’s
понимают что там огромные территории это
Tibet there Yes, there is an Indian Uyghur Yes
там Тибет Да есть индиан уйгурский Да
inside Mongolia Yes inner Mongolia
внутри Монголия Да внутренняя Монголия
Yes iner Mongolia is yes such a brother This is
Да инер Монголия есть да такой брат Это
China Yes what was China so far
кита Китай Да что там было пока Китаем
if you look at the manju Yes the dynasties that ruled Manju
если смотреть манджу Да правили манджу
would have been China there yes in fact
династии бы Китай там были да фактически
now they are starting to
это сейчас они тут начинают пальц там
take off their finger there ugute Dasha here in the
угуте снять Даше вот в
dynasty when U  Majuro, yes, Majuro
династии вот ког У маджуро да у маджуро
also, by the way, at a certain period the Chinese had a
тоже кстати было в определённый период
Uyghur
уйгурское
script Well, yes, but in short, there is
письмо у китайцев Ну да Но короче это
also a difference, like ska, they are like
Разница есть ещё типа как ска они вот
this Well, the Uyghur is like that, it's an Arabic
так Ну уйгурский вот так ти арабское
script No, it's a little wrong Wait
письмо Нет там немножко не так Подожди
Stop, the Arabs write on the left on the
Стоп арабы пишут слева на
uh On the right  from right to left, yes, the Arabs write
э-э Справа справа налево да арабы пишут
there a little bit. And by the way, you Well, the fact is
там немного А ты кстати Ну Дело в том
that the modern Uyghur and the Uyghur
что уйгурский современный и уйгурский
that was then are also, of course, so
который был тогда он тоже конечно
different. That’s because if you
отличается так Вот потому что если ты
looked at the
смотрел в
history, if you were interested in the history
ээ те если ты историю интересовался
of Moscow, these all sorts of princes, Yes, who
московские эти всякие князья Да которые
came to
приезжали э в
this  in the Horde to receive a label for a life, a
этот в Орду получать ярлык на жение
label is a letter. Yes, this is what they wrote out, then the
ярлык - это грамоту Да такою выписывали
label was written out in the Uyghur language,
то ярлык выписывал на уйгурском языке
but in the Empire in the Empire in the Empire of
же в импери в империи в Империи
Genghis Khan, the entire office was conducted in
Чингисхана канцелярия вся велась на
Uyghur because the Uyghurs were then a
уйгурском потому что уйгуры были тогда
very developed people, they were very written,
очень развитый народ очень письменный
and the Russians ran wild in the forests,
был да русские бегали в лесах дикие
you understand  in skins back then and here it was
понимаешь в шкурах ещё тогда а тут было
Yes yes yes
Да да да Согласно
According to now, anthropology is yes
Согласно сейчас антропология это да
anthropology is the science of man, like
антропология - это наука о человеке типа
human
человеческие
populations. That’s why I know this among people, for
популяции Я поэтому так в народах знаю я
example, I immediately looked at
вот например я же сразу посмотрел Да на
you, and like, well, damn, I understand that you’re like
тебя и типа ну блин понимаю что ты типа
you  not Chinese Well, you say I’m from China, I
ты не китаец Ну ты говоришь я из Китая я
see that you’re not Chinese, an anthropological
вижу что ты не китаец антропологический
type, you understand, I
тип понимаешь ты
also look like a Kazakh, I’m also Kazakh, I’m also
го ещё я похож на казаха ещё казах ещё
Kyrgyz, maybe Well, that’s what I’m I
Кыргыз может быть Ну вот то что я я
immediately Look, I immediately localize The fact is
сразу Смотри я сразу локализовать Дело в
that you definitely can’t say that
том что однозначно нельзя так сказать
there  for example, to the Buryats or I just
там например бурятам или я просто так
told the Buryats so that they can get
сказал бурятам вот для того чтобы тебя
behind you and you start giving out some things,
позади и ты начал выдавать какие-то вещи
but I immediately see it’s not Chinese because the
но я сразу вижу Не китайце потому что у
Chinese have a completely different anthropological
китайцев совсем другой антропологический
type, yes they have Well, apparently, put a
тип да у них вот Ну видно возьми поставь
Chinese and a Turk like you’ll see  This is
китайца и тюрка типа ты увидишь Это
a Chinese, this is not a
китаец это не
Chinese professional
китаец профессиональный про
about anthropology. So, after all,
име по антропологии Так что вс-таки
who do you study for, you get
На кого учишься получаешь
in linguistics, linguistics of the Russian
на лингвистике лингвистика русского
language. And why those linguistics of the Russian
языка А зачем те лингвистика русского
language? Well, how did I want to choose
языка Ну что как я хотел ти выбрать на
pure Russian, like phonetics,
чисто русский яы ещ типа фонетика ещё
morphology, I wanted
морфология я хотел
Yes, I  I thought that the Russian language is our great one,
Да я думал что русский язык наш Великий
yes And I have now, well, it’s
такой да А у меня у меня сейчас ну как
like my
бы моя
girlfriend, she’s
girlfriend она
from the Czech Republic herself from the Czech Republic, you know, Czech Republic
сама с Чехии с Чехии знаешь така Чехия
Yes, she’s a specialist in Slavic
Да она специалист по славянской
philology in Slavic philology and she
филологии по славянской филологии и она
just studied Russian and
как раз изучала и русский язык
Ukrainian, she showed me Why  The
украинский она мне показала Почему
Russian language is full-fledged, which is
русский язык полноценно что вот
Ukrainian, look, Ukrainians write
украинский смотри украинцы как пишут так
and read as they write, they write Milk and milk and
и читают они пишут Молоко да молоко и
read milk, Russians write milk and
читают молоко русские пишут молоко а
read milk. This is milk. Do you know
читают молоко Это молоко А знаешь
why? Because they, look, the
почему Почему Потому что им смотри
Russians brought a letter from Kiev from
русским письмо принесли из Киева из
Kievan Rus, so that’s the ancestors
Киевской Руси так вот то есть предки
They taught the Ukrainians how to write Russian
украинцев они их научили писать русских
Yes, the Ukrainians both wrote and read, and the
Да украинцы как писали так и читают а
Russian
русские
Ukrainians taught them to write in Ukrainian
украинцы их писать научили по-украински
Yes, and then they read Iverka They read
Да а они потом иверка Они читают по
one at a time And they speak differently, you understand,
одному А говорят по-другому понимаешь
but it’s just dialects, the influence of dialects or
а просто диалек влияние диалектов или
what Well, I honestly don’t remember  Well, look,
что Ну ну не честно не помню Ну смотри
look, the Russians didn’t have their own letter.
смотри у русских не было письма своего
Yes, the Russians were brought a letter from Kiev,
Да русским принесли письмо из Киева вот
if you look, the Kiev monks, yes, yes,
если ты посмотришь киевские монахи да да
they brought it from Kievan Rus, there were wild
из Киевской Руси принесли вот там дикие
tribes running around in these places And so
племена бегали в этих где сес И так
on there was savagery. Yes, they
дальше там дикость была Да туда
came there and taught them to write.  with these
приходили и учили их писать вот этими
Slavic initial letters and in Ukrainian in the
славянскими буквица да по-украински по
Ancient Ukrainian language Yes And so the
Древне украинскому языку Да И вот
Ukrainians wrote to them Milk yes
украинцы им написали Молоко да
They read milk and spoke somehow in
Они читали молоко а говорили как-то
their own way And that’s all
по-своему А вот и всё
And in short, if in Ukrainian Yak Just
А короче если на украинском яке Просто
milk is written and they still
молоко пис и всё также
read milk
прочитают молоко
here  just one to one Why why they
вот просто один в один Почему почему ру
read Russian like
русский читают типа
milk also look Russians write it and
молоко также смотри русские пишут его а
they read it
читают его его
Yes and the Ukrainians wrote it Wow and
Да а украинцы вот написали они Ого так и
I read
читаю
it all from them because their language
його у них всё потому что ихний язык
like it turns out to be more ancient than
типа получается более древний чем
Russian yes Russian came from Ukrainian
русский да русский пошёл от украинского
and  then
и потом
it deteriorated when, like, all the influences
испортился когда вот типа вся влияния
there were Finnish Turkic And so
там были там финский тюркский И так
on. Therefore, in order to understand Russian, you
дальше Поэтому чтобы понять русский
first need to be like Latin
нужно сначала вот это как латынь
for many European languages, and
для там многих европейских языков так и
for Slavic languages ​​you need to learn Ukrainian
для славянских нужно украинский выучить
when you learn Ukrainian, so I started with
когда учишь украинский вот я начал с
this fren of mine, it told me Little by little  like
этой своей френ она мне Понемногу типа
it allows you to learn Ukrainian Yes, I understand the essence of
даёт учить украинский Да я понимаю суть
Russian word formation Why did this
словообразование русские Почему так
happen?
получилось а
Well, yes, our Slavic language is very
Ну да у нас славянский язык очень
rich. I think you know, in short, the Russian
богатый Я думаю знаешь короче русский
language is very rich because
язык очень богаты пому что
the adjective is very much shorter in
прилагательный очень много короче на
English, even in English there are no
английском даже на английском нету
types of adjectives in
типа прилагательных ещё на китайском
our Chinese language  a few adjectives also have
языке у нас немного прилагательных ещё у
vaska mood Yes, you know that
васка наклонение Да вы знаете что
this is not a mood Like if you read like I
это не наклонение Типа если читать типа
read I read the
читаю я читаю
declension is not a mood but a declension to
склонение не наклонение а склонение
decline Yes the declension is very difficult
склонять Да склонение очень сложно
declension and conjugation Yes Yeah, very
склонение и спряжение Есть Угу очень
difficult this is the most difficult part I do yes
сложно это самая сложная часть Я ду да
because it is an inflected language
потому что это флективный язык
inflected
флективный
Yes, now Kazakh is what kind of language
да сейчас казахский - это какой язык
Now wait, I don’t know I don’t
Сейчас подождите не знаю Я казахский не
know Kazakh, it’s all
знав это все
simpler I was a little like that when I met a
проще Я немножко так когда встречался с
Chinese girl Yes,
девочкой китаянкой Да
she Brother, you know a lot, you’re just a
она Брат ты очень много знаешь б просто
genius Yes, I know,
гений Да я знаю да
yes Well, listen, I met a Chinese girl
Ну слушай я встречался с китаянкой
there after all  2 years we understand not
вс-таки там 2 года мы понимаешь не
only
только
you understood Ponya Andrey It’s very nice to
вы понял Поня Андрей Очень приятно
meet you anthropology I want to
познакомиться антропология Я хочу
learn but I just wanted to but now I
выучить но я хотел просто но сейчас мне
just don’t have the time if there’s time maybe I’m
просто не время если время может быть я
reading Where are you going then when
читаю А где собираешся потом когда
you graduate where are you going to
отучишься где собираешься
live maybe I
жить может быть
don’t know the teacher or the translator  I
не знаю преподаватель или переводчиком
know you’re going to China, yes, or
не знаю в Китай в Китаю едешь да Или
where I don’t know. I want to move to
куда не знаю Я хочу переехать в
Kazakhstan, I don’t know, or to Kazakhstan, but to
Казахстан не знаю или в Казахстан вот в
Kazakhstan, the Kazakhs, I look, I haven’t been to
Казахстан казахи я смотри я не был в
Kazakhstan, but I looked at the history of
Казахстане Но смотрел про историю
Kazakhstan. Yes, the Kazakhs are a very great people,
Казахстана Да казахи очень великий народ
these are, uh, these ones. Remember, remember the Kipchaks
это ж ээ вот эти Помнишь Помнишь кипчаки
Polovtsians were Yes, these are the ancestors of the Kazakhs and the
половцы были Да это ж предки казах да
Kipchaks, the steppe and look, if you
кипчаки степь и смотри если сейчас
look now at a huge huge territory,
смотреть огромная огромная территория
it would be a Kipchak Yes, uh, in Kazakhstan, there is a
это бы кипчак Да ээ в Казахстане э есть
very Wait, what is this city called,
очень Подожди как этот город называется
very ancient, the most ancient city in
очень древний самый древний город
Kazakhstan
Казахстана
m Taras Taras Taras Taras Yes, Taras
м Тарас Тарас Тарас Тарас Да Тарас
in my opinion Yes  He’s also
по-моему Да он ему сколько-то там тоже
like, very old, for some time, in short, when Moscow did
типа лет очень Короче когда Москвы ещё
n’t even exist yet, and if you look at
вообще не было да и если посмотреть
when the Muscovites Yes, the Russians, what kind of
когда э москвичи Да вот русские какая у
clothes do they wear? I always ask the Russians,
них одежда Я всегда русских спрашиваю
they made bast shoes from wood, they wove bast shoes,
они лапти из дерева делали плели лапти
and the
да
Kazakhs Yes, like other Slavic people here
казахи Да как и другие славянские тут
Il peoples Yes, they walked in leather
народы ильские Да они ходили в кожаной
shoes, you know, the Kazakhs didn’t wear bast shoes,
обуви понимаешь казах в лаптях не ходил
they already in those days also did
они уже в те времена тоже делали
saddled a horse, saddled Yes, they, uh,
оседлали лошадь оседлали Да они ээ
made leather harnesses and so on. Further, Yes, and what about
делали кожаную упряжь и так Дальше Да А
the Muscovites, they ran wild in the forests,
московиты что там они бегали в лесах
you know, they were like that. So the
дикие понимаешь были такое Так что
Kazakhs are very  strongly I, if
казахи очень сильно Я вот если как бы
somehow I go around Asia, I’ll definitely
как-то поеду по Азии обязательно в
go to Kazakhstan I wanted to stop by
Казахстан Хотел заехать
Thank you Thank you brother very cool very very
Спасибо Спасибо брат очень круто очень
cool Whenever I
очень круто Я когда
meet Kazakhs I always tell them
вре встречаю казахов Я им всегда говорю
Alga Kazakhstan they are just handsome
Алга Казахстан они просто красавчики
Yes, the
Да за
Internet is bad for development right now
слышно интернет плохо сечас
together
сообща
with I’m just  I’m interested in the Russian language,
с Я просто интересую на русский язык ещё
then I chose the Russian language. Well, here’s the
потом я выбрал русский язык Ну вот
linguistics of the Russian language. Well, maybe
лингвистика русского языка Ну может быть
in the future I don’t know how to teach them. Well,
в будущем преподавать их не знаю Ну
I don’t know for sure. I think that no one
точно не знаю я думаю что никому не
needs life in the future. In the future there will be English,
нужен быт в будущем будут там английский
Chinese, there will be several more languages,
китайский там ещё несколько языков
Russian; it’s Russian for no one. Russia  what can
русский он никому рус Россия что может
Russia give to the world, yes, you understand Look, everything
Россия дать миру да понимаешь Смотри всё
gives, uh, let’s say Russia took everything Yes,
даёт ээ скажем Россия всё что взяла Да
she stole everything from everyone Yes, take a
она всё украла у всех Да возьми
balalaika, this is a stolen Kazakh komuz
балалайка это украденный казахов комуз
Kama Yes, they just made a round
Каму Да только круглый сделали
triangular everything like I already speak Russian
треугольный всё типа уже я русски говорю
What kind of word is balalaika, this is not a Russian
Что за слово балалайка это не русское
word, you understand
слово понимаешь
money and I'm a Russian guitar yes yes You're
деньги а я русская гитара да да Ты как
like a philologist Look I'm
Ты как филолог Смотри я русских
asking Russians What does the word money mean yes
спрашиваю Что означает слово деньги да
it's Kazakh tenge in the Turkic
это же казахская теньге на тюркском
language money was tenge in Russian they
языке деньги было теньге по русские
took it and called it money for themselves that is,
взяли и назвали себе деньги то есть у
they have almost if you look at dumplings Yes it
них почти если смотре пельмени Да это
came too  like it’s not from Russia, it’s a
пришло тоже типа не из России это
Chinese dish Yes, if we look at what the
китайское блюдо Да если мы посмотрим что
Russians have their own There is nothing that
у русских своего Нет ничего нет что у
they have in their culture that’s all so come on
них в культуре вот и всё так что давай
Yes brother it’s in the Russians if you look at
Да брат это в у русских если смотреть
when the Golden Horde came yes that is, there are
когда Золотая Орда пришла да то есть там
Polovtsians cha Yes they brought it
половцы ча Да они принесли русским
some shoes for the Russians Yes, they gave them a little and they said
какую-то обувь Да немножко дали сказали
How can you live, yes, that is, they were running
Как можно жить да то есть они же бегали
there bosses and naked, you understand in these ti e
там боссы и голые понимаешь в этих ти э
if you look at Herodotus, Herodotus
если посмотреть геродота геродот
described that this is where the
описывал что там вот где сейчас
Moscow region is now Yes, the Andropharm tribes lived,
Московская область Да жили племена
only wild ones, they were still from the
андрофарм только дикие были они ещё из
tribal  the way of life has not completely come out.
родоплеменного уклада не совсем вышли
We are anthropologists who are also studying this.
Вот это мы антропологи тоже изучаем Вот
You may have noticed in many, uh, I don’t know
ты может замечал во многих ээ я не знаю
if they study with you because they study with you from
ли там у вас учатся потому что у вас с
different regions. Yes, but those
разных регионов учатся Да но вот те
that are Moscow, Yaroslavl region,
которые Московская Ярославская область
where Kostroma, they have a certain
где так Костромская у них определённый
kind  structure Jaws so
какой-то строение Челюсти такой
protruding I didn’t notice This is called
выпирающий не замечал Вот это называется
androphobia, from an anthropological point of
андрофобия вот с антропологической точки
view, androphobia jaw Yes, here they are,
зрения андрофобия челюсть Да вот они
for example, here’s a Kazakh Yes, you look like
э ты например вот казах Да ты похож на
those Kazakhs who lived there for 200, 300, 400
тех казахов которые жили там 200 300 400
years, it’s true that you are like your
лет правда вот ты такой есть на своих
ancestors and they look like  their ancestors Yes, these are their
предков и они похожи на своих предков Да
ancestors An Bustard Yes, they
вот ихние эти предки ан Дрофа Да они
had such a slightly
были с такой немножко
harsh jaw Yes, they, say, ate
жестковато челюстью Да они скажем жрали
raw meat ate raw meat Yes, and Ponya,
сырое мясо жрали сырое мясо Да а Поня
people survived who have strong
выживали люди которые вот с сильными
jaws, it turns out that the Kazakhs, for example,
челюстями получается вот казахи например
look at how many meat
посмотри вот у казахов сколько мясных
dishes the Kazakhs really have there  beshbarmak there is
блюд есть правда там бешбармак там
shish kebab and so on Yes, a huge culture
шашлык и так дальше Да огромная культура
Yes, they cooked meat Kazakhs will not eat
Да они готовили мясо казах не будет
raw horse meat, it’s true he will cook and
конину сырую есть правда он приготовит
make a lot of dishes yes And what kind Tell me
сделает куча блюд да А какие Вот скажи
What is the Russian national meat dish,
Какое у русских мясное блюдо
borscht borscht This is not Borscht - this is
национальное борщ борщ Это не Борщ - это
Ukrainian this is Ukrainian cuisine Yes Boshe
украинское это украинская кухня Да Боше
this  Ukrainian cuisine
это украинская кухня
Yes, I don’t know, but instead because the
Да не знаю вот Вот вместо потому что
Russians Yes, until the
русские Да вот пока им не принесли
European peoples brought them the Ukrainians, the Kazakhs
европейские народы украинцы там казахи
didn’t bring them any dishes, but they
не по приносили им какие-то блюда да они
reaped raw meat, if you look at Russian
жали сырое мясо если посмотришь русские
folk tales, they ate
народные сказки они ели
turnips, ate raw food Yes, Pushkin wrote there
репу ели сырую тр Да там Пушкин писал
Grandfather grated turnips; in short, this
репу натёр дед репку короче вот эта
fairy tale about Turnips can be read by Turnips,
сказка про Репку может читал Репка
in short, and it turns out that there
короче да и получается мясных блюд
are no meat dishes at all; they ate raw meat and
вообще нету они жрали сырое мясо и
therefore, in order to tear off raw meat, yes,
поэтому а сырое мясо чтобы отодрать да
like, that is, you need a huge jaw and
типа то есть нужно огромная челюсть и
evolution was going on. So individuals with weak
эволюция шла Так что особи со слабыми
jaws they are not  survived and therefore these
челюстями они не выживали и поэтому эти
andropharm the basis of the population had
андрофарм основа популяции было с вот
such a protruding jaw and now there are a
такой выпирающей челюстью и сейчас их
lot of them too, they are a little
много тоже вот есть они немножко
diluted with normal people, well,
разбавили с нормальными людьми вот ну
if you see such a jaw, this is what is
если видишь такой да челюсть Вот это это
called the Muscovy jaw, this is what is called in
называется Московия челюсть вот так в
anthropology
антропологии
Now I don’t I can’t  say nothing
Сейчас я не я не могу говорить ничего
in short shock in general in shock ra you read
короче шок вообще в шоке ра ты читали
read read a lot read a lot Prat a lot
читал много читал много Прат очень много
Well now I’m just I now you’re actually de
Ну сейчас я просто я сейчас ты вообще де
her brother well wait I’m still 43 years old
ней брат ну подожди мне всё-таки 43 года
and
а тебе
how old are you I’m now 20 22 Well you see I’m
сколько Мне сейчас 20 22 Ну вот видишь я
twice  older when you have 4
в два раза старше когда у тебе будет 4
You will also be well-read, you will know a lot
Ты тоже будешь начитанный будешь много
Yes, thank you, maybe this is
знать Да спасибо на может быть это это
experience Well, the fact is that look, we have a
опыт Ну Дело в том что смотри у нас
difference for as long as you have already lived, you
разница столько сколько ты уже прожил
understand, that is, understand that it still
понимаешь то есть пойми что это всё-таки
doesn’t fall from the sky like that  knowledge is all
с с неба так не падают знания это всё
the same, you’ve been reading there all these years,
равно ты же там читаешь эти все года да
yeah, in short, just for the sake of interest,
Угу короче вот ради ради интереса
look it up later Google Who are the
посмотри потом Погугли Кто такие
modern Androfarm region And so
андрофарм ской области современной И так
on Yes, these tribes of cannibals So
дальше Да вот эти племена людоедов Вот
they remained if the Kazakhs hadn’t
они и остались если бы казахи не
brought them Kazakhs like the Tatars and
принесли им вот казахи типа татары
others  the Turkic peoples did not bring them, let’s
другие тюркские народы не принесли им
say a little civilization, because the
э немножко скажем цивилизации потому
Golden Rada was a fairly civilized
золотая рда довольно цивилизованно было
state, yes, that is, there were cities and so
государство да то есть города были и так
on. Further Yes, and the Muscovites, in short, did
Дальше Да А у московитов что там короче
n’t even know how to read and write. So
даже читать писать Не умели Так что
yes, it’s true. It’s true. Well, I
да это правда Это правда Ну русские
don’t believe the Russians at all because  I
вообще не верю потому что
think just Thank you, say
думаю просто Спасибо говори
what they could bring If they have
что они могли принести Если у них нету
nothing national, nothing cultural,
ничего национального ничего культурного
yes, that is, all the characters in fairy tales that are
да то есть все персонажи сказок которые
passed off as Russian are Finno-Ugric
там выдают за русские это фино угорские
fairy tales, here is Baba Yoke Koschey Yes, there are
сказки вот баба ига Кощей Да Бессмертные
all sorts of immortals there, it’s all Finno-Ugric Hut
там всякие это всё фино угорский Избушка
on chicken legs This is Finnish Es  And so
на курьих ножках Это финский Эс И так
on, so
дальше так
that simple
что простого
SJ here in the world in the world there is nothing by chance,
СЖ вот в мире в мире не ничего случайно
that is, somewhere higher powers brought us together,
то есть где-то нас высшие силы свели
you see for some reason And you and me and you
видишь почему-то И меня с тобой и тебя
and me, somewhere there are plans for us to
со мной вот где-то замыслы чтобы мы
meet and enrich each other Here is
встретились и обогатили друг друга Вот
information  You are also a very positive
информацией Ты тоже очень позитивный
person, you know quite well, you don’t just
человек вот довольно знаешь не просто
know, there are people sitting there
знаешь там вот есть там сидят люди
drinking You’re learning, you’re developing, you’ve
бухают Ты учишься ты развиваешься ты в
been to America This is commendable
Америке побывал Это похвально
Yes, thank you, SBO, you’re in America, come on,
Да спасибо м СБО вы в Америке да давай у
I’ll have a lecture soon Come on, let’s write,
меня сейчас будет лекция скоро Давай
write,
тебе давай давай писал писал
Come on  I am in short for not
Давай я короче для не
God
Бог
thousand you are a couple of phrases on the Chinese
тыщ ты пару фраз на китайской
network Oh my God you are generally
сети О боже ты вообще
people like squeak comment God of
народ лайк писка комент Богу
anthropology China knowledge and just
антропологии Китае знавство и всего
in short
короче
Andra I can’t in short like
Андра я не могу короче лайкните
subscribe and send it to your friends so they can
подпишитесь и скиньте друзьям чтобы по
devour
пожрали
Pauly subscribe to inst I don’t know
Поли подпишись на inst Я не знаю для
what this is for  so why are you there to marvel at the
чого це тоб для чого тоб там дивитись на
oce face Ale for you tse odi two or three
оце фейс Але для тебе це оди два або три
clicks Ale ti trimae mene and I will be a kazati
клика Але ти тримае мене и я буду казати
in me there Kupa folov and in me there will be a
в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
classy set up Robi but cool video
класний настр щоб Роби но крут видео
write on th Ista pok Andriy
пись на й Иста пок Андрий
So come on  cell
Так давай ячка
with
с